type Question = {
  question: string;
  answers: string[];
  correctAnswer: string;
};


export const E1cellcyclegametogenesisdata = { 
  questions: [
    
        {
            question: "Which phase of the cell cycle is responsible for DNA synthesis?",
            answers: ["G1",
             "S",
             "G2",
             "M",
             "C"],
            correctAnswer: "S",
        },
        {
            question: "During which phase does the cell prepare for mitosis?",
            answers: ["G1",
             "S",
             "G2",
             "M",
             "C"],
            correctAnswer: "G2",
        },
        {
            question: "What occurs during the G1 phase of the cell cycle?",
            answers: ["DNA synthesis",
             "Preparation for division",
             "Mitosis",
             "Cell growth",
             "Cytokinesis"],
            correctAnswer: "Cell growth",
        },
        {
            question: "In which phase does mitosis occur?",
            answers: ["G1",
             "S",
             "G2",
             "M",
             "C"],
            correctAnswer: "M",
        },
        {
            question: "What is the main event during the M phase?",
            answers: ["DNA replication",
             "Preparation for division",
             "Separation of genetic material",
             "Cell growth",
             "Nuclear envelope breakdown"],
            correctAnswer: "Separation of genetic material",
        },
        
              {
                question: "Primordial germ cells (PGCs) are formed in which layer during the second week?",
                answers: ["Mesoderm",
                 "Ectoderm",
                 "Epiblast",
                 "Endoderm",
                 "Hypoblast"],
                correctAnswer: "Epiblast",
              },
              {
                question: "During which week do primordial germ cells migrate to the wall of the yolk sac?",
                answers: ["Second week",
                 "Third week",
                 "Fourth week",
                 "Fifth week",
                 "Sixth week"],
                correctAnswer: "Fourth week",
              },
              {
                question: "By which week do primordial germ cells arrive at the developing gonads?",
                answers: ["Fourth week",
                 "Fifth week",
                 "Sixth week",
                 "Seventh week",
                 "Eighth week"],
                correctAnswer: "Fifth week",
              },
              {
                question: "Primordial germ cells migrate through which structure during gastrulation?",
                answers: ["Neural tube",
                 "Notochord",
                 "Primitive streak",
                 "Somite",
                 "Blastopore"],
                correctAnswer: "Primitive streak",
              },
              {
                question: "What process do primordial germ cells undergo to prepare for fertilization?",
                answers: ["Differentiation",
                 "Mitosis",
                 "Gametogenesis",
                 "Cleavage",
                 "Gastrulation"],
                correctAnswer: "Gametogenesis",
              },
              {
                question: "Which of the following occurs after gametogenesis?",
                answers: ["Meiosis",
                 "Cytodifferentiation",
                 "Mitosis",
                 "Crossing over",
                 "Synapsis"],
                correctAnswer: "Mitosis",
              }
            ] as Question[]
          };

    //           ,
    //           {
    //             "question": "In humans, how many genes are approximately found on 46 chromosomes?",
    //             "option1": "10,000",
    //             "option2": "20,000",
    //             "option3": "23,000",
    //             "option4": "30,000",
    //             "option5": "46,000",
    //             "ans": 3
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "Which chromosomes determine the genetic sex of an individual?",
    //             "option1": "Autosomes",
    //             "option2": "Chromatids",
    //             "option3": "Sex chromosomes",
    //             "option4": "Homologous chromosomes",
    //             "option5": "Polar bodies",
    //             "ans": 3
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "What is the process called whereby one cell divides to give rise to two genetically identical daughter cells?",
    //             "option1": "Meiosis",
    //             "option2": "Cytokinesis",
    //             "option3": "Synapsis",
    //             "option4": "Mitosis",
    //             "option5": "Crossover",
    //             "ans": 4
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "During which phase of mitosis do chromosomes line up in the equatorial plane?",
    //             "option1": "Prophase",
    //             "option2": "Metaphase",
    //             "option3": "Anaphase",
    //             "option4": "Telophase",
    //             "option5": "Prometaphase",
    //             "ans": 2
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "How many cell divisions are required in meiosis?",
    //             "option1": "One",
    //             "option2": "Two",
    //             "option3": "Three",
    //             "option4": "Four",
    //             "option5": "Five",
    //             "ans": 2
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "What term describes the exact point-for-point pairing of homologous chromosomes during meiosis?",
    //             "option1": "Crossover",
    //             "option2": "Synapsis",
    //             "option3": "Cytokinesis",
    //             "option4": "Chromatid",
    //             "option5": "Chiasma",
    //             "ans": 2
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "How many chromosomes does a human gamete contain?",
    //             "option1": "22",
    //             "option2": "23",
    //             "option3": "44",
    //             "option4": "46",
    //             "option5": "48",
    //             "ans": 2
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "Which event during meiosis enhances genetic variability?",
    //             "option1": "DNA replication",
    //             "option2": "Cytokinesis",
    //             "option3": "Crossing over",
    //             "option4": "Chromosome condensation",
    //             "option5": "Mitosis",
    //             "ans": 3
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "How many daughter cells are produced from one primary spermatocyte?",
    //             "option1": "One",
    //             "option2": "Two",
    //             "option3": "Three",
    //             "option4": "Four",
    //             "option5": "Five",
    //             "ans": 4
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "What structure temporarily unites chromatids during crossover in meiosis I?",
    //             "option1": "Centromere",
    //             "option2": "Spindle fiber",
    //             "option3": "Chiasma",
    //             "option4": "Synaptonemal complex",
    //             "option5": "Kinetochores",
    //             "ans": 3
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "Which cells receive little cytoplasm and degenerate during oogenesis?",
    //             "option1": "Primary oocytes",
    //             "option2": "Spermatocytes",
    //             "option3": "Secondary oocytes",
    //             "option4": "Polar bodies",
    //             "option5": "Somatic cells",
    //             "ans": 4
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "What restores the diploid number of chromosomes at fertilization?",
    //             "option1": "Mitosis",
    //             "option2": "Crossover",
    //             "option3": "Fusion of gametes",
    //             "option4": "Cytokinesis",
    //             "option5": "Synapsis",
    //             "ans": 3
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "Which process involves the separation of sister chromatids?",
    //             "option1": "Mitosis",
    //             "option2": "Meiosis I",
    //             "option3": "Meiosis II",
    //             "option4": "Crossover",
    //             "option5": "Synapsis",
    //             "ans": 3
    //           },
    //           {
    //             "question": "Which structure forms during prophase and attaches chromosomes to centrioles?",
    //             "option1": "Centromere",
    //             "option2": "Mitotic spindle",
    //             "option3": "Chiasma",
    //             "option4": "Nucleus",
    //             "option5": "Nuclear envelope",
    //             "ans": 2
    //           },
              
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What process differentiates oogonia into mature oocytes?",
    //                 "option1": "Spermatogenesis",
    //                 "option2": "Mitosis",
    //                 "option3": "Meiosis",
    //                 "option4": "Oogenesis",
    //                 "option5": "Fertilization",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "At what stage do primary oocytes arrest during prenatal development?",
    //                 "option1": "Metaphase I",
    //                 "option2": "Anaphase I",
    //                 "option3": "Prophase I",
    //                 "option4": "Telophase I",
    //                 "option5": "Prophase II",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //             },
    //             // {
    //             //     "question": "What is the maximum estimated number of germ cells in the ovary by the fifth month of prenatal development?",
    //             //     "option1": "1 million",
    //             //     "option2": "3 million",
    //             //     "option3": "5 million",
    //             //     "option4": "7 million",
    //             //     "option5": "9 million",
    //             //     "ans": 4
    //             // },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What is a primary oocyte surrounded by a single layer of flat epithelial cells called?",
    //                 "option1": "Secondary follicle",
    //                 "option2": "Graafian follicle",
    //                 "option3": "Primordial follicle",
    //                 "option4": "Antral follicle",
    //                 "option5": "Zona pellucida",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What hormone is responsible for maintaining the arrested state of primary oocytes?",
    //                 "option1": "Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)",
    //                 "option2": "Luteinizing hormone (LH)",
    //                 "option3": "Oocyte maturation inhibitor (OMI)",
    //                 "option4": "Estrogen",
    //                 "option5": "Progesterone",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "Approximately how many primary oocytes are present by the beginning of puberty?",
    //                 "option1": "100,000",
    //                 "option2": "200,000",
    //                 "option3": "300,000",
    //                 "option4": "40,000",
    //                 "option5": "600,000",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What stage do primary oocytes reach immediately before ovulation?",
    //                 "option1": "Prophase I",
    //                 "option2": "Metaphase II",
    //                 "option3": "Anaphase II",
    //                 "option4": "Telophase I",
    //                 "option5": "Metaphase I",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "Which cells provide support and nutrition to developing sperm cells?",
    //                 "option1": "Leydig cells",
    //                 "option2": "Spermatogonia",
    //                 "option3": "Sertoli cells",
    //                 "option4": "Granulosa cells",
    //                 "option5": "Theca cells",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What is the term for the transformation of spermatids into spermatozoa?",
    //                 "option1": "Spermatogenesis",
    //                 "option2": "Meiosis",
    //                 "option3": "Mitosis",
    //                 "option4": "Spermiogenesis",
    //                 "option5": "Oogenesis",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "Which hormone stimulates testosterone production in Leydig cells?",
    //                 "option1": "FSH",
    //                 "option2": "LH",
    //                 "option3": "Estrogen",
    //                 "option4": "Progesterone",
    //                 "option5": "OMI",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What structure forms a glycoprotein layer on the surface of the oocyte?",
    //                 "option1": "Zona pellucida",
    //                 "option2": "Antrum",
    //                 "option3": "Theca folliculi",
    //                 "option4": "Granulosa cells",
    //                 "option5": "Cumulus oophorus",
    //                 "ans": 1
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What is the fate of most primary oocytes during childhood?",
    //                 "option1": "They become mature oocytes",
    //                 "option2": "They remain arrested in metaphase II",
    //                 "option3": "They degenerate and become atretic",
    //                 "option4": "They undergo mitosis",
    //                 "option5": "They enter meiosis II",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "Which cells secrete the oocyte maturation inhibitor (OMI)?",
    //                 "option1": "Sertoli cells",
    //                 "option2": "Leydig cells",
    //                 "option3": "Granulosa cells",
    //                 "option4": "Follicular cells",
    //                 "option5": "Theca cells",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "How long does it take for a spermatogonium to develop into a mature spermatozoon?",
    //                 "option1": "60 days",
    //                 "option2": "74 days",
    //                 "option3": "90 days",
    //                 "option4": "45 days",
    //                 "option5": "30 days",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What is the role of the acrosome in spermatozoa?",
    //                 "option1": "To provide energy for movement",
    //                 "option2": "To condense the nucleus",
    //                 "option3": "To assist in penetration of the egg",
    //                 "option4": "To form the tail",
    //                 "option5": "To protect the DNA",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "Which cells in the male infant can be recognized in the sex cords of the testis?",
    //                 "option1": "Spermatogonia",
    //                 "option2": "Spermatocytes",
    //                 "option3": "Spermatids",
    //                 "option4": "Primordial germ cells",
    //                 "option5": "Spermatozoa",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What marks the initiation of spermatogenesis?",
    //                 "option1": "Formation of Sertoli cells",
    //                 "option2": "Division of type A spermatogonia",
    //                 "option3": "Entry of primary spermatocytes into prophase",
    //                 "option4": "Completion of meiosis II",
    //                 "option5": "Formation of spermatids",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "What happens to the first polar body during oocyte maturation?",
    //                 "option1": "It develops into a mature gamete",
    //                 "option2": "It receives most of the cytoplasm",
    //                 "option3": "It undergoes mitotic divisions",
    //                 "option4": "It usually degenerates",
    //                 "option5": "It becomes a primary oocyte",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "Which phase do primary oocytes enter just before ovulation?",
    //                 "option1": "Metaphase I",
    //                 "option2": "Anaphase I",
    //                 "option3": "Prophase II",
    //                 "option4": "Metaphase II",
    //                 "option5": "Telophase II",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
    //             {
    //                 "question": "Which cells become theca folliculi during follicle development?",
    //                 "option1": "Sertoli cells",
    //                 "option2": "Leydig cells",
    //                 "option3": "Follicular cells",
    //                 "option4": "Stromal cells",
    //                 "option5": "Granulosa cells",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //             },
                
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn is diagnosed with a teratoma containing hair, bone, and muscle. From which type of cells are these tumors thought to arise?",
    //                 "option1": "Somatic cells",
    //                 "option2": "Pluripotent stem cells",
    //                 "option3": "Multipotent stem cells",
    //                 "option4": "Unipotent cells",
    //                 "option5": "Differentiated cells",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A fetus is identified with a chromosomal abnormality leading to spontaneous abortion. What is the most common chromosomal abnormality found in abortuses?",
    //                 "option1": "Turner syndrome",
    //                 "option2": "Triploidy",
    //                 "option3": "Trisomy 16",
    //                 "option4": "Trisomy 21",
    //                 "option5": "Klinefelter syndrome",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A pregnant woman over the age of 35 is at increased risk of having a child with which chromosomal abnormality?",
    //                 "option1": "Turner syndrome",
    //                 "option2": "Trisomy 13",
    //                 "option3": "Trisomy 18",
    //                 "option4": "Trisomy 21",
    //                 "option5": "Klinefelter syndrome",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A male newborn is diagnosed with Klinefelter syndrome. What is the chromosomal complement of this condition?",
    //                 "option1": "45, X",
    //                 "option2": "47, XXY",
    //                 "option3": "47, XYY",
    //                 "option4": "48, XXYY",
    //                 "option5": "46, XY",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn with Turner syndrome presents with several physical abnormalities. What is the karyotype associated with Turner syndrome?",
    //                 "option1": "45, X",
    //                 "option2": "46, XX",
    //                 "option3": "47, XXY",
    //                 "option4": "47, XXX",
    //                 "option5": "48, XXXY",
    //                 "ans": 1
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic feature of patients with trisomy 21?",
    //                 "option1": "Intellectual disability",
    //                 "option2": "Microcephaly",
    //                 "option3": "Cat-like cry",
    //                 "option4": "Large testes",
    //                 "option5": "Gynecomastia",
    //                 "ans": 1
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn is found to have a partial deletion of the short arm of chromosome 5. What syndrome is associated with this genetic defect?",
    //                 "option1": "Turner syndrome",
    //                 "option2": "Cri-du-chat syndrome",
    //                 "option3": "Down syndrome",
    //                 "option4": "Klinefelter syndrome",
    //                 "option5": "Fragile X syndrome",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A child with Angelman syndrome is observed to have unprovoked and prolonged periods of laughter. Which chromosome is affected in this condition?",
    //                 "option1": "Chromosome 5",
    //                 "option2": "Chromosome 13",
    //                 "option3": "Chromosome 15",
    //                 "option4": "Chromosome 18",
    //                 "option5": "Chromosome 21",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn presents with holoprosencephaly, congenital heart defects, and cleft lip and palate. Which trisomy is most likely present?",
    //                 "option1": "Trisomy 13",
    //                 "option2": "Trisomy 18",
    //                 "option3": "Trisomy 21",
    //                 "option4": "Monosomy X",
    //                 "option5": "Triploidy",
    //                 "ans": 1
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "What is a common feature of trisomy 18 (Edwards syndrome)?",
    //                 "option1": "Cleft lip and palate",
    //                 "option2": "Polydactyly",
    //                 "option3": "Congenital heart defects",
    //                 "option4": "Webbed neck",
    //                 "option5": "Large ears",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn has microdeletion syndrome with intellectual disability, hypotonia, and hypogonadism. Which syndrome is this likely to be?",
    //                 "option1": "Down syndrome",
    //                 "option2": "Fragile X syndrome",
    //                 "option3": "Prader-Willi syndrome",
    //                 "option4": "Angelman syndrome",
    //                 "option5": "Klinefelter syndrome",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "Fragile X syndrome is characterized by intellectual disability and large testes. What is the genetic cause of this syndrome?",
    //                 "option1": "Trisomy 21",
    //                 "option2": "Partial deletion of chromosome 5",
    //                 "option3": "Triploidy",
    //                 "option4": "CGG repeats in the FMRI gene",
    //                 "option5": "Monosomy X",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn with Turner syndrome exhibits lymphedema of the extremities. What other feature is common in Turner syndrome?",
    //                 "option1": "Gynecomastia",
    //                 "option2": "Webbed neck",
    //                 "option3": "Large ears",
    //                 "option4": "Cleft lip",
    //                 "option5": "Polydactyly",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A female patient is diagnosed with triple X syndrome. Which of the following is a common issue in these patients?",
    //                 "option1": "Speech problems",
    //                 "option2": "Cardiac defects",
    //                 "option3": "Hypotonia",
    //                 "option4": "Micrognathia",
    //                 "option5": "Holoprosencephaly",
    //                 "ans": 1
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn with Trisomy 18 is expected to have a high mortality rate. What is a common feature of this syndrome?",
    //                 "option1": "Webbed neck",
    //                 "option2": "Microcephaly",
    //                 "option3": "Craniofacial abnormalities",
    //                 "option4": "Low-set ears",
    //                 "option5": "Large ears",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A patient with cri-du-chat syndrome has a distinct cat-like cry. Which chromosome is partially deleted in this syndrome?",
    //                 "option1": "Chromosome 5",
    //                 "option2": "Chromosome 15",
    //                 "option3": "Chromosome 21",
    //                 "option4": "Chromosome 18",
    //                 "option5": "Chromosome X",
    //                 "ans": 1
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn with trisomy 13 (Patau syndrome) has microphthalmia and severe intellectual disability. Which other feature is commonly associated with this syndrome?",
    //                 "option1": "Webbed neck",
    //                 "option2": "Gynecomastia",
    //                 "option3": "Congenital heart defects",
    //                 "option4": "Large ears",
    //                 "option5": "Hypotonia",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "Which diagnostic technique is used to assess chromosome number and integrity in cytogenetic analysis?",
    //                 "option1": "PCR",
    //                 "option2": "Western blotting",
    //                 "option3": "ELISA",
    //                 "option4": "Giemsa staining",
    //                 "option5": "Microarray",
    //                 "ans": 4
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A fetus is diagnosed with mosaicism, where some cells have an abnormal chromosome number. How does mosaicism typically arise?",
    //                 "option1": "Nondisjunction during meiosis",
    //                 "option2": "Nondisjunction during mitosis",
    //                 "option3": "Unbalanced translocation",
    //                 "option4": "Balanced translocation",
    //                 "option5": "Point mutation",
    //                 "ans": 2
    //               },
    //               {
    //                 "question": "A newborn with Down syndrome has an increased risk of developing which condition?",
    //                 "option1": "Gynecomastia",
    //                 "option2": "Microphthalmia",
    //                 "option3": "Leukemia",
    //                 "option4": "Cat-like cry",
    //                 "option5": "Holoprosencephaly",
    //                 "ans": 3
    //               }            
            
            
    // ]        
          
    
    
    // // [{
    // //     "question": "What is the initial cell formed when an oocyte is fertilized by a sperm?",
    // //     "option1": "Blastocyst",
    // //     "option2": "Zygote",
    // //     "option3": "Morula",
    // //     "option4": "Embryo",
    // //     "option5": "Gastrula",
    // //     "ans": 2
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "During which period do the most visible advances in human development occur?",
    // //     "option1": "Neonatal period",
    // //     "option2": "Infancy",
    // //     "option3": "Embryonic period",
    // //     "option4": "Fetal period",
    // //     "option5": "Adolescence",
    // //     "ans": 3
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "The process by which a fertilized oocyte is transformed into a multicellular human being is termed as?",
    // //     "option1": "Apoptosis",
    // //     "option2": "Differentiation",
    // //     "option3": "Gastrulation",
    // //     "option4": "Human development",
    // //     "option5": "Cell migration",
    // //     "ans": 4
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "Which period is characterized by the transition from intrauterine to extrauterine existence?",
    // //     "option1": "Infancy",
    // //     "option2": "Neonatal period",
    // //     "option3": "Childhood",
    // //     "option4": "Adolescence",
    // //     "option5": "Adulthood",
    // //     "ans": 2
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "At what age range is full growth and maturity generally reached in humans?",
    // //     "option1": "13 to 15 years",
    // //     "option2": "15 to 18 years",
    // //     "option3": "18 to 21 years",
    // //     "option4": "21 to 25 years",
    // //     "option5": "25 to 30 years",
    // //     "ans": 3
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "Which term refers to the development of bone during childhood?",
    // //     "option1": "Ossification",
    // //     "option2": "Calcification",
    // //     "option3": "Myelination",
    // //     "option4": "Mineralization",
    // //     "option5": "Chondrification",
    // //     "ans": 1
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "What is the critical period during which most congenital malformations occur?",
    // //     "option1": "Neonatal period",
    // //     "option2": "Fetal period",
    // //     "option3": "Infancy",
    // //     "option4": "Embryonic period",
    // //     "option5": "Adulthood",
    // //     "ans": 4
    // // },
    // // // {
    // // //     "question": "What is the function of the placenta during fetal development?",
    // // //     "option1": "Produce antibodies",
    // // //     "option2": "Absorb dietary fats",
    // // //     "option3": "Exchange of nutrients and waste products between mother and fetus",
    // // //     "option4": "Filter lymph",
    // // //     "option5": "Store red blood cells",
    // // //     "ans": 3
    // // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "Which developmental period occurs after birth?",
    // //     "option1": "Prenatal period",
    // //     "option2": "Embryonic period",
    // //     "option3": "Fetal period",
    // //     "option4": "Postnatal period",
    // //     "option5": "Prepubertal period",
    // //     "ans": 4
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "What is the term for the period when humans become functionally capable of reproduction?",
    // //     "option1": "Infancy",
    // //     "option2": "Neonatal period",
    // //     "option3": "Childhood",
    // //     "option4": "Puberty",
    // //     "option5": "Adulthood",
    // //     "ans": 4
    // // },
    // // // {
    // // //     "question": "What is the approximate duration of the embryonic period in human development?",
    // // //     "option1": "0-2 weeks",
    // // //     "option2": "3-8 weeks",
    // // //     "option3": "9-12 weeks",
    // // //     "option4": "13-20 weeks",
    // // //     "option5": "21-28 weeks",
    // // //     "ans": 2
    // // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "Which term refers to the study of birth defects and their causes?",
    // //     "option1": "Embryology",
    // //     "option2": "Developmental anatomy",
    // //     "option3": "Teratology",
    // //     "option4": "Fetology",
    // //     "option5": "Postnatal development",
    // //     "ans": 3
    // // },
    // // // {
    // // //     "question": "What is the main focus of clinically oriented embryology?",
    // // //     "option1": "Study of plant embryos",
    // // //     "option2": "Prenatal development of humans",
    // // //     "option3": "Development of teeth",
    // // //     "option4": "Growth in childhood",
    // // //     "option5": "Reproductive health",
    // // //     "ans": 2
    // // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "Which of the following structures is formed first during embryonic development?",
    // //     "option1": "Heart",
    // //     "option2": "Liver",
    // //     "option3": "Lung",
    // //     "option4": "Kidney",
    // //     "option5": "Brain",
    // //     "ans": 1
    // // },
    // // {
    // //     "question": "Which term is used to describe an infant aged 1 month or younger?",
    // //     "option1": "Toddler",
    // //     "option2": "Neonate",
    // //     "option3": "Preschooler",
    // //     "option4": "Adolescent",
    // //     "option5": "Newborn",
    // //     "ans": 2
    // // },]
    







    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which germ layer gives rise to the nervous system?",
    //     //     "option1": "Endoderm",
    //     //     "option2": "Mesoderm",
    //     //     "option3": "Ectoderm",
    //     //     "option4": "Epiblast",
    //     //     "option5": "Hypoblast",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "At what stage does the zygote become a blastocyst?",
    //     //     "option1": "Morula",
    //     //     "option2": "Gastrula",
    //     //     "option3": "Blastula",
    //     //     "option4": "Neurula",
    //     //     "option5": "Embryonic",
    //     //     "ans": 1
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which structure is formed by the trophoblast cells?",
    //     //     "option1": "Embryo",
    //     //     "option2": "Amnion",
    //     //     "option3": "Chorion",
    //     //     "option4": "Placenta",
    //     //     "option5": "Allantois",
    //     //     "ans": 4
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What is the primary function of the yolk sac in humans?",
    //     //     "option1": "Nutrition",
    //     //     "option2": "Respiration",
    //     //     "option3": "Waste removal",
    //     //     "option4": "Blood cell formation",
    //     //     "option5": "Protection",
    //     //     "ans": 4
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "During which week does gastrulation occur?",
    //     //     "option1": "First",
    //     //     "option2": "Second",
    //     //     "option3": "Third",
    //     //     "option4": "Fourth",
    //     //     "option5": "Fifth",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "The primitive streak is important for the formation of which structure?",
    //     //     "option1": "Neural tube",
    //     //     "option2": "Heart",
    //     //     "option3": "Somites",
    //     //     "option4": "Notochord",
    //     //     "option5": "Placenta",
    //     //     "ans": 4
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What is the role of the notochord in embryonic development?",
    //     //     "option1": "Forming the neural crest",
    //     //     "option2": "Signaling neural tube formation",
    //     //     "option3": "Creating the heart tube",
    //     //     "option4": "Developing the somites",
    //     //     "option5": "Initiating gastrulation",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which structure forms the outer layer of the blastocyst?",
    //     //     "option1": "Epiblast",
    //     //     "option2": "Hypoblast",
    //     //     "option3": "Trophoblast",
    //     //     "option4": "Amnion",
    //     //     "option5": "Yolk sac",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What does the intermediate mesoderm give rise to?",
    //     //     "option1": "Heart",
    //     //     "option2": "Kidneys",
    //     //     "option3": "Lungs",
    //     //     "option4": "Liver",
    //     //     "option5": "Brain",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which structure is responsible for oxygen and nutrient exchange between mother and fetus?",
    //     //     "option1": "Amniotic sac",
    //     //     "option2": "Chorion",
    //     //     "option3": "Yolk sac",
    //     //     "option4": "Placenta",
    //     //     "option5": "Allantois",
    //     //     "ans": 4
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What does the sclerotome part of the somite become?",
    //     //     "option1": "Skin",
    //     //     "option2": "Muscles",
    //     //     "option3": "Vertebrae",
    //     //     "option4": "Nervous tissue",
    //     //     "option5": "Lungs",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which cells are responsible for producing the extracellular matrix in connective tissues?",
    //     //     "option1": "Osteoblasts",
    //     //     "option2": "Chondroblasts",
    //     //     "option3": "Fibroblasts",
    //     //     "option4": "Myoblasts",
    //     //     "option5": "Adipocytes",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "During which process do primary germ layers form?",
    //     //     "option1": "Fertilization",
    //     //     "option2": "Gastrulation",
    //     //     "option3": "Organogenesis",
    //     //     "option4": "Neurulation",
    //     //     "option5": "Morphogenesis",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What does the hypoblast contribute to?",
    //     //     "option1": "Placenta formation",
    //     //     "option2": "Amniotic cavity",
    //     //     "option3": "Yolk sac",
    //     //     "option4": "Neural tube",
    //     //     "option5": "Somites",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which hormone is essential for the maintenance of the corpus luteum during early pregnancy?",
    //     //     "option1": "FSH",
    //     //     "option2": "LH",
    //     //     "option3": "Estrogen",
    //     //     "option4": "Progesterone",
    //     //     "option5": "hCG",
    //     //     "ans": 5
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which structure connects the embryo to the placenta?",
    //     //     "option1": "Amnion",
    //     //     "option2": "Chorion",
    //     //     "option3": "Yolk sac",
    //     //     "option4": "Umbilical cord",
    //     //     "option5": "Allantois",
    //     //     "ans": 4
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which germ layer forms the lining of the digestive tract?",
    //     //     "option1": "Ectoderm",
    //     //     "option2": "Mesoderm",
    //     //     "option3": "Endoderm",
    //     //     "option4": "Epiblast",
    //     //     "option5": "Hypoblast",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "When does the heart begin to beat in the developing embryo?",
    //     //     "option1": "End of 2nd week",
    //     //     "option2": "End of 3rd week",
    //     //     "option3": "End of 4th week",
    //     //     "option4": "End of 5th week",
    //     //     "option5": "End of 6th week",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What does the epiblast give rise to?",
    //     //     "option1": "Trophoblast",
    //     //     "option2": "Hypoblast",
    //     //     "option3": "All three germ layers",
    //     //     "option4": "Amnion",
    //     //     "option5": "Yolk sac",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which cells in the embryo are responsible for forming the nervous system?",
    //     //     "option1": "Endoderm cells",
    //     //     "option2": "Mesoderm cells",
    //     //     "option3": "Ectoderm cells",
    //     //     "option4": "Epiblast cells",
    //     //     "option5": "Hypoblast cells",
    //     //     "ans": 3
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What does the neural crest give rise to?",
    //     //     "option1": "Neural tube",
    //     //     "option2": "Peripheral nervous system",
    //     //     "option3": "Somites",
    //     //     "option4": "Notochord",
    //     //     "option5": "Amnion",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which process is characterized by the formation of the primitive streak?",
    //     //     "option1": "Neurulation",
    //     //     "option2": "Gastrulation",
    //     //     "option3": "Organogenesis",
    //     //     "option4": "Morphogenesis",
    //     //     "option5": "Blastulation",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "During which week of development does the neural tube close?",
    //     //     "option1": "3rd week",
    //     //     "option2": "4th week",
    //     //     "option3": "5th week",
    //     //     "option4": "6th week",
    //     //     "option5": "7th week",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which hormone is primarily responsible for maintaining the uterine lining during pregnancy?",
    //     //     "option1": "Estrogen",
    //     //     "option2": "Progesterone",
    //     //     "option3": "FSH",
    //     //     "option4": "LH",
    //     //     "option5": "hCG",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "Which cells form the blood-brain barrier?",
    //     //     "option1": "Neurons",
    //     //     "option2": "Astrocytes",
    //     //     "option3": "Oligodendrocytes",
    //     //     "option4": "Microglia",
    //     //     "option5": "Schwann cells",
    //     //     "ans": 2
    //     // },
    //     // {
    //     //     "question": "What is the main function of the zona pellucida?",
    //     //     "option1": "Provide nutrients",
    //     //     "option2": "Protect the oocyte",
    //     //     "option3": "Facilitate fertilization",
    //     //     "option4": "Prevent polyspermy",
    //     //     "option5": "Secrete hormones",
    //     //     "ans": 4
    //     // },
        
    

